《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
抱歉你卷进了这些事中
I'm sorry you had to get mixed up in this,
我相信你一定是个诚实的好姑娘
because I'm sure you're a... good, honest girl, really.
-我要消失了 -你不能这么做
- I'm gonna disappear. - But you can't do that!
-我不是在征求你的意见  -你不能消失
- I wasn't asking. - You can't disappear!
你得和我一起回家
You have to come back home with me.
等戈登警探找到杀害我父母的凶手
When Detective Gordon finds the man who killed my parents,
你得作证
you have to testify.
暂时留他俩一命
I want these two alive for now.
你怎么敢用我神圣的母亲来对付我
How dare you use my sainted mother against me?
你要为此付出代价
You'll suffer for that.
快点道别吧
Say your good-byes quickly.
穆尼女士还有地方要去呢
Ms. Mooney has places to go.
你好啊  菲什
Hello, Fish.
本剧集字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译制作
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再整理而成
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
翻译：艾瑞卡   夜影章鱼X   charcie   爵士年代蓬蓬裙
翻译：Reginamoon   哥谭直属   草草   DustD   Silence
时间轴：艹明   宝宝   凭陵新月
特效&后期：宝宝          校对&总监：草草
你们就是备胎组了吧
Well, you must be the B team.
我们只管转移
We just handle transpo.
鲍勃会好好照顾你的
Bob will be taking care of you.
鲍勃
Bob.
我们最厉害的人之一
One of our top guys.
你就放心吧
You're in good hands.
早上好
Good morning.
你起得早啊
You're up early.
我都没睡
I haven't made it to bed yet.
据说有人撞见你和汤普金斯医生
Word is you got caught with Doc Thompkins
在更衣室里
in the locker room.
只是公事
Strictly business.
-有菲什的消息吗  -没有
- Any word on Fish? - No.
俱乐部被血洗了  没找到菲什
Club's all shot up, blood everywhere, no sign of Fish.
要怪也是怪她自己
It's her own damn fault.
她道上混的  知道这些风险
She played the game, she knew the risks.
抱歉  哈维  我知道你喜欢她
Sorry, Harv, I know you have a thing for her.
我谁都不喜欢
I don't got a thing for nobody.
我喜欢我自己
My thing is for me.
如果说有谁能从那种困境中爬出来
If anyone can make it out of a scrape like that,
只有菲什  她指甲利着呢
it's Fish-- the woman's nails.
来吧  还有案子
Come on, we got a case.
好  什么案子
Yeah. What do we got?
为民除害型凶杀
Public service homicide.
被害人是个混蛋
Vic's a douche.
弗拉斯  这位是戈登
Flass. Gordon.
戈登  这位是弗拉斯
Gordon. Flass.
弗拉斯在缉毒组工作
Flass works Narcotics.
所以这么珠光宝气  还穿一身肯定很贵
Hence the bling and the, uh, no doubt expensive
但看着很廉价的意大利西服
yet somehow cheap-looking Italian suit.
布洛克  还是乱穿衣服
Ah, Bullock, still dressing in the dark
闻起来像个酒馆妓女
and smelling like a taphouse whore.
弗拉斯的线人告诉他的尸体在这儿
One of Flass's connections tipped him off on the body.
跟戈登讲讲这小子吧
Why don't you tell Gordon about the kid.
平奇・利特菲尔德
Pinky Littlefield.
一个叫上城刺客组织的毒贩
Dealer from a crew known as the Uptown Assassins.
他在这个街区活动
He works this block. Well...
至少生前是
least he did.
他身上有毒品吗
Any drugs on him?
一点也没找到
Didn't find any.
要我猜  最多就是交易谈崩了
My big wild guess: deal gone bad.
这种人  早晚是这个下场
Kid like this, bound to happen sooner or later.
如我所说
Like I said,
为民除害型凶杀
public service homicide.
好了  如果你们不用人手把手教了
Well, boys, I've got another case I've got to attend to,
我还有别的案子要处理
so if you don't need any more hand-holding.
我送你出去
I'm gonna walk you out.
警员们可能找到了一个目击证人
Hey, unis think they may have found a witness.
夜间清洁工
Night janitor.
他们正带他过来
They're bringing him over.
吉姆  温克勒先生
Jim, Mr. Winkler.
先生
Sir.
不用这么正式
No need for the formalities.
叫我利昂吧
Call me Leon.
利昂
Leon.
很感谢你能站出来
We really appreciate you stepping forward.
我妻子路易莎常说  不挺身而出
My wife Louisa always says, if you don't step forward,
就是后退
you step back.
听起来是个睿智的女人
She sounds like a smart lady.
没错
Yes, she is.
要我录口供吗
So, uh, do I give a statement?
描述一下凶手
A description of the killer?
我不了解这种事的规矩
I'm not sure how this works.
能不能麻烦你来一趟警局
Would you be willing to come down to the precinct,
和速写师弄一张画像出来
work with a sketch artist?
这是抓住凶手最好的办法了
That really is the best way to catch the killer.
会帮我们大忙的
It'd be a huge help.
行啊
Of course.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
是  亲爱的  我还在警局呢
Yes, sweetheart, I'm still at the precinct.
我知道
I know.
当然了  是啊
Of course, yeah.
-好  -速写师来了吗
- Okay. - They send in the sketch artist yet?
没  还没来
No, not yet.
路易莎  我得挂了
Louisa, I have to go.
再见
Bye-bye.
但你确实看见凶手了  对吧
But you did see the killer, right?
是的  之前我也是这么跟警探说的
Uh, yes, that's what I told the detectives earlier.
抱歉  您是哪位
I'm sorry, who are you?
怎么会出这种事
How the hell did this happen?
房间内外的监控都被关掉了
Security cameras inside and outside the room were turned off.
爱德  知道是什么凶器了吗
Ed, you got any thoughts on the weapon?
什么东西能撞沉巨轮
What's strong enough to smash ships
却见不得日光
but still fears the sun?
别扯什么谜语了  爱德
Can it with the riddles, Ed.
我今天没这闲情逸致  以后也不会有
I don't have the patience today or any day.
-冰  -正确
- Ice. - Correct.
从伤口的大小来判断
Gauging by the small circumference of the wounds,
我认为凶器是一把冰锥
I believe the weapon is an ice pick.
碳钢材质  15厘米长
Carbon steel, six inches long.
插得很深  以致压迫周围的组织
Driven in deep enough that it marked the surrounding tissue
使伤口形成了一个独特的六边形
with an imprint of a distinctive hexagonal handle.
你家厨房里一般用不到这个
It's not your standard kitchen fare.
还有个好玩的事  先生们
Fun fact, gentlemen:
温克勒先生的伤口
Mr. Winkler's wounds here
和今天早上被害人身上的完全一致
are the exact same as the wounds on the victim from this morning.
那个毒贩利特菲尔德
The drug dealer? Littlefield?
就是他  同一把凶器
Him. Same weapon.
这样说来凶手大概也一样
Same killer, one would suppose.
可恶
Damn it.
在警察地盘上杀人
Right in our house.
好了
Okay.
你叫什么
What is your name?
你明知故问
You know who I am.
就是走个程序
It's just a formality.
我
I...
再确认一下
like to be sure.
鲍勃  是吧
Bob, hmm?
是罗伯特的昵称吗
Is that short for Robert?
你有家人吗  罗伯特
You have any family, Robert?
两个可爱的女儿
Two lovely daughters.
我把你登记为玛利亚・梅赛德斯・穆尼
I'm putting you down as Maria Mercedes Mooney,
也就是菲什
aka Fish.
今天就是要让你诚心诚意悔过
We'll be extracting a very sincere apology from you today.
应该花不了多久
Shouldn't take too long.
你女儿多大了  罗伯特
How old are your girls, Robert?
我敢打赌  她们肯定都很丑
I bet you they're some ugly little creatures.
别这样  菲什
Now, come on, Fish.
没必要这么无礼
No call for rudeness.
只有我朋友才能叫我菲什  亲爱的
Only my friends call me Fish, darling.
而你和我
And you and I,
可不是朋友
we're not friends.
还不是
Yet.
哥谭
第一季  第十三集
你去带他下来
You go get him.
我得找下焚化炉的钥匙
I got to find the keys to the incinerator.
马可
Hey, Marco.
菲什・穆尼在哪
Where's... Fish... Mooney?
还有谁会相信我们警察能保护人民安全
How is anyone gonna trust us to keep them safe?
连警局里的人都保护不了
We can't protect people in our own house.
好消息是这地方都是罪犯
Upside is the place crawling with criminals,
可供选择的嫌犯非常多
so we got beaucoup suspects to choose from.
这算什么好消息
That's an upside?
监控录像被关掉了
Security cameras were turned off.
可能是警察干的
Could've been a cop.
很可能就是
Probably was.
你想都别这么想
You do not even think something like that.
一旦让外面那些人
The second that those guys out there
听到你认为凶手是警察
hear that you're looking at a cop,
他们一定会搞死你
they are gonna turn on you.
布洛克说得没错  你要是把矛头指向他们
Bullock's right; you start pointing fingers,
你的复职都会搭上
you could jeopardize your reinstatement.
要有确凿的证据
You need concrete evidence
才能考虑指责其他警察杀人
to even think of accusing another officer of murder.
我先去查值班警卫工作日志
I'll start with the guard duty logbook.
-吉姆  -温克勒是我的证人
- Jim... - Winkler was my witness.
我绝不会让凶手逍遥法外
No way I'm letting this ride.
我叫他来的  我一定找到凶手
I asked him to come in here, I'm gonna find his killer.
不管他是谁
No matter who it is.
一定要谨慎行事
Proceed with caution.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
要我同意后才能采取行动
No big moves without my say-so.
我觉得
I do believe
这个街区我们已经转了两遍了  布鲁斯少爷
this is the second time we've been around this block, Master Bruce.
塞琳娜喜欢在这附近转悠
Selina likes to hang out here.
值得反复找
It's worth doubling back.
再说了  你应该心满意足了
Besides, you got what you wanted.
我照你说的出了城
I went out of town like you asked.
去了好几周
For weeks.
这儿不是不安全吗
Yeah, well... It wasn't safe here, was it?
那些刺客又不是来抓我的
The assassins weren't after me.
他们要抓的是她
They were after her.
听好了  一旦有危险
Yeah, and we'll be back on that plane straight back to
你立马跟我上飞机回阿尔卑斯山
the bloody Alps the first sign of trouble, I tell you.
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce.
布鲁斯少爷  回车里来
Master Bruce, get back in the car now.
就沿着这条街走一圈
Can we walk around the block just once?
然后我就上车
Then I'll get back in the car.
求你了  阿尔弗雷德
Please, Alfred.
走一圈  就回家
Once around the block and then home.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你以后有的是时间
Got the rest of your life like that
被女人鬼迷心窍
to get whipped into a frenzy by the females.
怎么现在就这么着急开始了
I don't know why you want to start now.
不是这样的
It's not like that.
滚开
Out of my way.
艾薇
Ivy?
小心  布鲁斯少爷
Steady, Master Bruce.
她好像有兽疥癣
Looks like she's got the mange.
我说是谁呢
Look who it is.
亿万富翁布鲁斯・韦恩
Billionaire Bruce Wayne.
你是谁  他保镖吗
Who are you, his bodyguard?
如果需要的话我就是  女士
If needs be, miss, yes.
包里什么东西
What's in the bag?
是给塞琳娜的
It's for Selina.
你见过她吗
Have you seen her?
当然  你愿意的话我可以帮你给她
Sure. I can give it to her if you want.
要不你帮我给她传个话
Perhaps you could pass on a message for me.
告诉她我在找她
Tell her I'm looking for her.
20块
20 bucks.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
20块
20 bucks.
小姐  给
There we are, miss.
你的朋友还真讨人喜欢啊  布鲁斯少爷
Delightful friends you have, Master Bruce.
回家吧
Home.
你就这点能耐吗
That's all you got?
你快让我无聊死了  小子
You are gonna bore me to death, fella.
真是厉害
That's impressive.
想要不同的手法吗
Different strokes, eh?
就拿我来说吧
You know, me,
我就不能吃辣
I can't stand hot spicy food,
可我妻子非常喜欢吃辣
but my wife, you know, she loves it.
越辣越好
Hotter the better.
我们该从哪开始好呢
Now where, oh, where are we gonna begin?
锯掉一只手很让人崩溃啊
Now, taking off a hand, that's devastating.
可我发现
But I've found
把膝盖敲碎...
that taking out a knee...
没事吧  菲什
You okay, Fish?
这本工作日志少了一页
A page is missing from this logbook.
光是这一条
Now, that in and of itself
就足以把你开除出警队
is grounds for dismissal from the force.
我要问的是
So my question to you is
今早在审讯室外值勤的是谁
who was on guard duty outside of interrogation this morning?
不知道啊
No idea, man.
没人愿意交代
Nobody's talking.
他们在互相包庇
They're protecting their own.
或者他们就是不爽你
Or they just don't like you.
面对现实吧  哈维
Face it, Harvey.
杀死利昂・温克勒的凶手是个警察
Leon Winkler's killer is a cop.
证据不足
Not proven.
少来了  你了解这些人的
Come on, you know these guys.
你认识这些人很久了
You've known them since way back.
给我点筹码  给我个切入点
Give me some leverage. Give me an angle.
你真的想和凶手共事吗
You really want to work with a murderer?
有人在哥谭市警局被杀了
Somebody gets whacked in the GCPD.
肯定要有人因此被解雇
Somebody's gonna get fired for this.
不会是我
Not me, pal.
格罗佛
Grover.
我们有个可靠的线人说
We got a reliable guy
是你撕掉了值班警卫工作日志上的那一页
says it was you pulled the page from the guard duty logbook.
不可能  你这话是哪听来的
No way. W-where did you get that?
-你听谁说的  -阿尔瓦雷斯说的
- Who said that? - Alvarez.
如果他这么说  那他就是在撒谎
If he said that, that son of a bitch is lying.
他为什么要撒谎
Why would he lie?
六年前  我和他妻子有过一腿
Look, six years ago, I had a thing with his wife, okay?
六年前
Six years ago.
他是个记仇的混蛋
He is a vindictive bastard.
这我们不管
Well, look, that's none of our business, huh?
从我们的立场来看
Look at it from our point of view.
我们得找到罪魁祸首
We got to find the culprit.
上头下令要我找出来
Brass demands one.
可不是我啊
But it wasn't me.
那是谁
Then who was it?
特拉华  有人看到特拉华吗
Delaware? Anybody seen Delaware?
看到他去车库了
Saw him go to the garage.
特拉华
Delaware.
你肯定会后悔的
You're gonna regret that.
今早在审讯室门外值勤的是你吧
You were guarding interrogation this morning, weren't you?
给我滚开
Screw off.
吉姆
Jim.
你在搞什么
What the hell are you doing?
你就不能悄悄地拘捕他
You couldn't bring him in here quietly,
然后带他去没人看到的地方吗
put him in some back room?
你这是要当众示威吗
You making some kind of statement?
没错
Damn right I am.
我警告过你了  你却当耳边风
I warned you and you didn't listen.
我有证据  和昨天早上在案发现场
I have evidence: the same drugs I found in Littlefield's shoe
我在利特菲尔德鞋里找到的毒品一样
at the crime scene yesterday morning.
这份证物属于一宗正在进行的秘密缉毒案件
That evidence is part of an ongoing undercover narco investigation.
你觉得我们会信这种鬼话吗
You expect us to believe that?
吉姆  缉毒组已经深入调查
Jim, narco's been knee-deep in
上城区毒品交易好几个月了
the Uptown drug trade for months.
我安排了很多卧底  他们为了这个案子
I've got a matrix of undercovers that have put their lives
都是拼上了命的
at stake for this investigation.
你刚刚那一出要是传出去
Your little stunt gets out,
整个行动都会暴露
you unravel the whole operation.
再说你的搜查也是非法的
Not to mention, the search was illegal.
那我们就无视特拉华与温克勒被杀的关联吗
So we're ignoring Delaware's involvement in Winkler's death?
是这样吗  警监
Is that what we're doing, Cap?
不是  但你这样不行  吉姆
No. But this isn't the way, Jim.
我要把案子交给内务处了
I'm turning over the case to Internal Affairs.
内务处
I.A.?
给那两个地下室里的酒鬼
Two old drunks in the basement.
你和布洛克将不再负责温克勒的凶杀案
You and Bullock are no longer investigating the Winkler murder.
那利特菲尔德的案子呢
What about the Littlefield murder?
等等  那是不是也属于
Or, wait, is that also a part of
一宗正在进行的缉毒案件
an ongoing narco investigation?
那案子归你  伙计  有什么需要尽管开口
All you, buddy. Let me know if you need any help.
抱歉发生了这种误会
I'm sorry about the confusion.
有什么事吗
Can I help you with something?
知道吗  柯林格小姐  最早的贺卡
Did you know, Miss Kringle, that the earliest greeting cards
可以追溯到15世纪的德国
dated back to Germany in the 1400s?
我挺忙的
I have a lot of work to do.
这是给你的
This is for you.
上面没什么奇怪的话吧
Doesn't say anything weird, does it?
完全没有  小姐
No, ma'am.
悠着点
Take it easy.
我没事  布奇
I'm fine, Butch.
给  敷敷
Here, try this.
你还好吗
You okay?
我快饿死了
I'm starving.
你真个汉子
You are one tough cookie.
谢谢你  布奇
Thank you, Butch.
听我说  我们得赶紧跑路了
Listen, we should hit the road.
估计不到一小时  法尔科内就会发现...
I figure we've got about an hour before Falcone...
找不到企鹅  我哪也不去
Oh, I'm not going anywhere until I find Penguin.
是他把莉莎的事告诉法尔科内的
He's the one that told Falcone about Liza.
老大  你大概不记得了
Boss, I don't know if you remember,
昨晚我们的人全被清光了
but as of last night, we don't have any men.
法尔科内会让全城的人找我们的
Falcone's gonna have the whole city looking for us.
不杀了企鹅  我哪也不会去的
I'm not going anywhere until I cut Penguin's throat.
一  二  三
One... two... three.
觉得如何  母亲
What do you think, Mother?
太美了
Oh, it's beautiful.
真有档次
So classy.
好像歌剧院一样
Like an opera house.
大吊灯
A chandelier.
和家里似的
Like home.
有人落下了一条丝巾
Someone left a scarf.
多衬我的裙子啊
It's beautiful with my dress.
谁捡到就是谁的
Finders keepers.
现在你是这家夜店的老板了吗
And now you are in charge of this club?
你把我准备的惊喜都毁了
Spoiled my surprise.
别这样  小可爱
No. Oh, no, no, liebchen.
别生气啊
No, don't be angry. No.
真是个好消息
Such good news.
我儿子有了自己的夜店
My boy has a club.
将会有一家夜店
Will have a club.
现在还有一些问题没有解决
There's still a few loose ends to tie up,
但是很快它就会是我的了
but... soon it will be mine.
我太为你感到骄傲了
I am so proud of you...
简直无法言喻
I could spit.
听着  吉姆  有些事我得告诉你
Listen, Jim, there's something I got to tell you.
几年前  弗拉斯和他的人
A few years ago, Flass and his people
开始逮捕毒贩  侵占他们的藏货屋
started busting drug dealers, taking over their stash houses,
然后拿来自己经营
running them themselves.
现在
Now?
你现在才告诉我
You tell me this now?
我是随机应变的那种
Look, I respond to crises as they arise.
我不像你那样提前做计划
I'm not a forward planner like you.
我当时没告诉你
I didn't tell you then
因为我怕你又头脑发热起来
because I didn't want to get you all riled you up,
现在我告诉你是想阻止你
but I'm telling you now because I want you to stop.
弗拉斯是有人的
Flass is protected.
谁
By who?
有权势的人
Serious people.
很高层  大财主
Really high up. Big money.
说不定  局长也有份
For all I know, the commissioner gets a piece, too.
你敢惹弗拉斯  就连阿卡姆也别想回了
You mess with Flass, you can forget going back to Arkham.
这些家伙可不是闹着玩的
These guys do not play.
那些藏货屋
These stash houses--
你能查到它们的地址吗
think you can get me a location on them?
你没有听我刚才的话吗
Did you not hear a word I just said?
藏货屋可以给我们将弗拉斯与利特菲尔德
The stash houses could give us evidence linking Flass
被杀关联起来的证据
to Littlefield's murder.
咱们用利特菲尔德拿下他
We nail him for Littlefield,
也就可以拿下温克勒的案子
we can nail him for Winkler.
我不能坐视不管  哈维
I can't let it be, Harvey.
你早该明白了
You should know that by now.
米克  是哈维
Mick, it's Harv.
还记得你和唐尼在搞的那事吗
You know that thing you and Donnie were working on?
弗拉斯那个
The Flass thing?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
做藏货屋的好地方
Prime spot for a stash house.
是呀
Yeah.
特拉华
Delaware,
把盒子交出来
hand over the boxes.
你就是学不乖  对吧
You don't learn, do you?
给我滚开
Get out of my face.
没必要动粗啊  先生们
No need to rough each other up, gentlemen.
我有搜查令
I got a warrant.
给了我们搜查与扣押的权利
Giving us the legal right to search and seizure.
看来这间仓库是上城刺客的
Seems this warehouse was being used as a home base
主基地
by the Uptown Assassins.
你指望我们相信你有一张签署过的搜查令
You expect us to believe you got a signed warrant
来收缴你自己的藏货屋吗
to clear your own stash house?
是局长下的令
On the commissioner's request.
法官签署过的
Signed by Judge Bam-Bam.
看来你不占理啊
Guess you don't have a leg to stand on...
凶案组的
homicide.
-咱们下一步怎么办  -下一步
- So what's our next step? - Next step?
我们没有证据证明弗拉斯与贩毒或两桩凶案有关
We got nothing to tie Flass to the drugs or the murders.
一桩凶案
Murder.
就一起
Just one.
内务处刚判定温克勒的死为自杀
Internal Affairs just ruled Winkler's death as a suicide.
他们准备将尸体还给他妻子了
They're releasing the body to his wife.
利昂是那么快乐
Leon was so very happy.
这不可能的...
This just can't be right. Can't be...
自杀
A suicide?
他用冰锥捅了自己的后背
He stabbed himself in the back with an ice pick?
这太荒谬了
That's absurd!
这么快就出结果说明局长插手了
A ruling this quick means the commissioner was involved.
去他的局长
Screw the commissioner.
你追查下去会危及我们所有人的工作
Going forward with this puts all of our jobs at risk.
听着  我想帮你  吉姆
Look, I want to help you, Jim.
哥谭市警局里是有人想帮你的
There are people here in GCPD who want to help you.
-那他们为什么不帮呢  -他们帮了
- So why don't they? - They have.
我也帮了
I have.
而我们也吸取了教训
And we learned the hard way.
对弗拉斯这种人  光说说可不够
With men like Flass, you need more than words.
要有结果
You need results.
而这次这是不可能的了
And that's not gonna happen this time around.
所以帮所有人一个忙
So do us all a favor
去查下一个案子吧
and move on to the next vic.
拜托了
Please.
你要去哪里
Where you going?
一小时后回来
Back in an hour.
听听  真是经典啊
Listen to this. This is classic.
够了  拜托
Stop it. Come on.
有什么的
Come on.
"亲爱的柯林格小姐
"Dear Miss Kringle,
你的眼睛如青草一般翠绿
your eyes are as green as a meadow.
你的微笑如太阳一般耀眼
Your smile is as bright as the sun.
你的肌肤如雪花一般洁白
Your skin is as white as a snowflake.
看来你的生活非常有趣"
It seems like your life is fun."
-不是吧  -你好啊
- Really? - Oh, hey!
作者本人来了哦
It's the writer himself. Whew.
写得可真不错啊  变态
It's a real piece of work you got there, perv.
我劝你还是别辞了工作去干这个吧
I wouldn't quit your day job if I were you.
收到
Roger, dodger.
-收到  -别说了
- Roger, dodger? - Stop it.
真是个怪胎
What a creep.
一二三  一二三
One, two, three. One, two, three.
一二三  一...
One, two, three. One...
你终于掌握了
Now... now you are getting it.
你块头这么大  还真是优雅
You are so graceful for such a big man.
他是不是很优雅呀  奥斯瓦尔德
Isn't he graceful, Oswald?
是啊  母亲
Yes, Mother.
吉姆
Jim.
欢迎
Welcome.
请吧
Come in.
派对上又来了一位帅哥
Another handsome man at the party.
我真幸运
I am so lucky.
这位是吉姆・戈登
This is Jim Gordon,
我和您提过的那位警探朋友
the detective friend I was telling you about.
真高兴见到奥斯瓦尔德的朋友
Oh. So nice to meet a friend of Oswald's.
我是格特鲁德・卡佩普特
I am Gertrud Kapelput.
很高兴见到您  卡佩普特太太
Nice to meet you, too, Mrs. Kapelput.
母亲  吉姆和我还有要事得办
Mother, Jim and I have very important business.
不嘛  真遗憾  太遗憾了
No. Oh, sad. Oh, how sad.
现在庆祝未免有点早了吧
A little soon to be celebrating, don't you think?
别傻站着啊
Well, don't just stand there.
坐吧
Sit.
不会说很久的
This won't take long.
我坚持  坐下
I insist. Sit.
我很高兴你打电话给我  吉姆・戈登
I'm so very glad you called, Jim Gordon.
我们太久没见面了
It's been far too long since we've seen each other.
我还想你是不是忘了我了
I was beginning to think you'd forgotten about me.
我需要你帮个忙
I need a favor.
你对一位名叫阿诺德・弗拉斯的
Do you know anything about a narcotics detective
缉毒警探有所了解吗
by the name of Arnold Flass?
我听过这个名字
I've heard the name.
我因为一起凶杀案正在调查他和他的人
I'm investigating him and his crew for murder,
但是我碰壁了
but I've hit a wall.
他的关系网太强大了
He's too well-connected.
我想着既然马罗尼在经营毒品生意
I figured since Maroni runs the drug trade,
也许你能找到有弗拉斯把柄的人
maybe you could find somebody with the goods on Flass?
-但是...  -嘘  不用再说了
- But... - Shh. Say no more.
这个忙我帮了
Favor is done.
我去打几个电话
I'll make some calls.
我欠你的该怎么还呢
And what do I owe you in return?
朋友间是互不相欠的  傻瓜
Friends don't owe friends, silly.
而是出于意愿互相帮助
They just do favors because they want to.
因为是朋友嘛
Because they're friends.
-不能有人受伤  -当然
- Nobody gets hurt. - Of course.
不会有人受伤
No one gets hurt.
来点香槟
Champagne.
天哪
Oh, dear me.
发生了什么
What happened here?
通知法尔科内
Call Falcone.
那还用说
No kidding.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
谢谢你们  伙计们  棒极了
Thank you, boys. Lovely.
不要  我还在跳呢  安静
No. I-I am dancing still. Shh.
-你们可以走了  -怎么就让他们走了
- You may go. - Oh, why you make them go?
盖布  你去帮助我的好朋友吉姆的时候
Gabe, on your way to help my dear friend Jim,
能好心顺便送我母亲回家吗
could you be a gentleman and take Mother home?
当然  老大
Sure thing, boss.
来吧  卡太太
Come on, Mrs. K.
一座宫殿
A palace.
我儿子有一座宫殿
My boy has a palace.
真是个好孩子
Such a good boy.
别担心
Don't worry.
我会回来的
I will be back.
女士们先生们  朋友们
Ladies and gentlemen, friends,
来自世界各地的名流们
celebrities from around the world,
我叫奥斯瓦尔德・科波特
my name is Oswald Cobblepot.
终于等到了这一天
Here we are at last.
我带着深深的诚挚和喜悦
It is with deep and sincere pleasure
欢迎你们来到我新夜总会的
that I bid you welcome to the official grand opening
盛大开业典礼
of my newest night spot, the...
不错啊
Not bad.
我觉得你的表现力得更强势点
I do believe you need to project more.
好让观众更加兴奋
Just to create a bit more excitement for the audience.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎来到菲什・穆尼夜店
welcome to Fish Mooney's!
就像那样
Like that.
什么样的怪人会跟自己下棋
What kind of weirdo plays chess with himself?
你不是有个管家陪你玩的吗
Don't you have a butler to do that kind of stuff with you?
他在做午饭
He's making lunch.
我收到你的信息了
I got your message.
我很高兴你没事
I'm glad you're safe.
阿尔弗雷德逼我出了城
Alfred made me go out of town.
瑞士  我们在那里有座房子
Switzerland. We have a house there.
算是座牧屋吧
Chalet, I guess.
牧屋
A chalet?
实际上就是座房子
It's basically a house.
你干吗要见我
Why did you want to see me?
我们是朋友  对吧
We're friends, aren't we?
你满世界开着车找我
You've been driving around looking for me,
托人捎信  怎么了
sending messages. What's up?
我有个礼物要给你
I got you a present.
看上去很像我们去的那个瑞士城镇
It looks like the town we stayed in.
谢谢你
Thank you.
还有  我想问你...想不想
Also, I wanted to know if, um... if you wanted to stay here
住在我家
in my house.
为什么
Why?
我觉得我们能互相帮助
I figure we can help each other out.
你能帮我找到杀害我父母的凶手
You can help me find the man who killed my parents,
我可以给你个更好的地方住
and I can give you a better place to live.
这里怎么就更好了
What's better about it?
听着  小子  别激动过头了
Listen kid... chill.
我来是想叫你别再来找我麻烦了
I came here to tell you to stop hassling me.
找你麻烦
Hassling you?
对
Yeah.
你开始招我烦了
You're beginning to bug me.
我们不是朋友吗
I thought we were friends.
听着  我撒谎了
Listen, I lied.
我没看到是谁杀了你父母
I... didn't see who killed your parents.
我没看到他的脸
I didn't see his face.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我撒谎是为了不被关进少管所
I lied so I wouldn't get locked up in juvie.
你给我买礼物  捎信  或是套近乎
So it's no use buying me presents or sending me messages
都是没用的
or trying to hang out.
毫无意义的  因为我帮不了你
There's no point because I can't help you.
平奇・利特菲尔德两周没付钱了
Pinky Littlefield was light two weeks running.
不付钱是要付出代价的
If you don't pay up, there's consequences.
弗拉斯杀他  是为了震慑他人
Flass killed him to send a message.
求你  我就知道这么多了
But please, please! I swear that's all I know.
你确定
You sure?
我发誓啊
I swear, man, I swear!
我相信你
I believe you.
但我需要更切实的证据
But I think I'll need something a bit more tangible.
不要啊  求你了
No, no, no! Please, no!
不要  求你
No! No! Please, no!
我发誓啊  我发誓
I swear, man! I swear!
现在觉得演艺圈好混吗
How are you liking show business now?
求您  穆尼女士
Please, Miss Mooney.
您这是在犯下错误
You're making a mistake.
我求您  让我说句话
I-I beg of you, let me speak.
我知道我们有分歧
I know we've had our differences.
我们可以联手
We could combine our forces.
想想我是怎么骗过所有人的吧
Think how'd we fool everyone.
我跟你联手吗
Me... work with you?
是我捡到了你
I found you.
是我成就了你
I made you.
你走进来的时候  不过是个心怀大志的小人物
When you walked in here, you were a sad little wannabe.
你还记得吗  布奇
Remember that, Butch?
你是那么害怕
You were so afraid.
抖得厉害
Shook like a leaf in fall.
你就是个下人
You're a servant.
伞童
An umbrella boy.
你就是...无名小卒
You're... A nobody.
我这个无名小卒还是每次都高你一招
This nobody still outfoxed you at every turn.
我一直都是法尔科内的人
I was working for Falcone the whole time!
你却完全没发现
And you didn't have the sense to see it!
你们好
Hello.
看来今天大家都想来穆尼的场子呢
Seems like Mooney's is the place to be today.
快走  走啊
Come on, come on!
-不要  -走吧
- No! - Come on!
走啊
Go, go, go!
来
Here.
你得走了
You got to go!
我拖住他们
I'll slow them down.
-不行  -走吧
- No, no! - Go!
又见了
Hello again.
她哪去了
Where is she?
怎么样  姑娘们
What do you think, girls?
要杀了他
Should we kill him...
还是带回家玩玩
or should we take him home to play with?
尼格玛先生
Mr. Nygma?
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle.
打扰你了吗
Am I interrupting?
是的  我在清除我外卖里的洋葱
Yes. I'm surgically removing the onions from my takeout,
如果你没别的事...
so if you don't mind...
尼格玛先生  我欠你个道歉
Mr. Nygma, I owe you an apology.
卡片不是我给阿诺德的
I didn't give Arnold the card.
是他自己在我桌上看到的
He found it in my desk.
他这人的幽默感很奇怪
He has a strange sense of humor.
我觉得你的卡片
I thought your card was...
很
very...
贴心
thoughtful.
算是吧
I guess.
总之  抱歉
Anyway, I'm sorry.
柯林格小姐  你愿意...
Miss Kringle, would you...
不不  别再说话了
No, no, no, no, no. Please, don't say anything else.
别说了
Just, please.
有希望哦
There's hope.
这是什么
What's this?
凶器和特拉华供出弗拉斯杀人的录音带
Murder weapon and a tape of Delaware rolling on Flass.
那小子挺滑头
Smart cookie, that one.
弗拉斯把冰锥给他  让他扔掉
Flass gave him the ice pick to throw away.
特拉华却给留了下来  以备不时之需
Delaware kept it in case he had to cover his own ass.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce?
她在撒谎
She was lying.
这样啊
I see.
我该去拿扫帚吗
Shall I get a broom, then?
还是你要守着
Or would you rather continue crying
破碎的美梦
over the shattered fragments of your...
哭鼻子
young dreams?
没错  阿尔弗雷德
Yes, Alfred.
去拿扫帚吧
A broom.
好的  布鲁斯少爷
Very good, Master Bruce.
我会找到其他线索的
I'll find other leads.
当然了
No doubt.
我就知道她不靠谱
I knew she was a wrong 'un.
阿诺德・弗拉斯
Arnold Flass.
你因杀害利昂・温克勒被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Leon Winkler.
走开吧  蠢蛋  你什么证据都没有
Keep walking, mutt. You got nothing.
够去州北蹲20年了
That's 20 years upstate right there.
特拉华把你供出来了
Delaware gave you up.
吉姆
Jimbo...
你真以为这些人会允许你逮捕我吗
you really think these guys are gonna let you arrest me?
他们都是我哥们
These are my friends.
这是我的地盘
This is my house.
这不是你的地盘
This is not your house.
你是个毒贩  是个杀人犯
You're a drug dealer and a murderer.
你不属于这里
You don't belong here.
你不配戴警徽
You don't deserve the badge.
你们能相信这种人吗
You believe this crap?
你才来多久
How long you been here?
几个月
A few months?
过五年再来教训我吧
Why don't you come preach to me in five years?
他杀了利昂・温克勒
He murdered Leon Winkler,
一个无辜者  他信任我们
an innocent man who trusted us!
他信任这个
Who trusted this.
以至于站出来  帮我们解决一宗案件
Enough to step forward and help us solve a case.
弗拉斯警探为了自保  杀了他
A man who died so Detective Flass could protect himself.
内务处说他是自杀
I.A. ruled it a suicide.
我要逮捕他
I'm arresting this man.
别傻了  蠢货  我有人罩着
Get real, dumb-ass. I'm protected.
你们可以帮我  也可以阻止我
You can help me or you can try and stop me.
不论如何
Either way,
我要履行职责
I'm doing my duty.
都给我滚远点
Hey, back off, all right?!
我有人的  你们少来
I'm protected! Get out of here.
闭嘴吧  弗拉斯
Shut up, Flass.
阿诺德・弗拉斯  你因杀人被捕了
Arnold Flass, you're under arrest for murder.
你在做什么  你疯了吗
The hell do you think you're doing? Are you crazy?
给他宣读权利
Read him his rights.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你所说的一切都将成为呈堂证供
Anything you say can and will be used against you...
你们不能关我
You can't keep me in here!
知道我认识多少人吗
You know how many people I got?
谢谢  警监
Thanks, Cap.
哥谭市  哥谭港
来
Here.
有什么打算
So what's the plan?
我要离开这里  躲一阵
I'm gonna leave town, lay low for a while.
然后我会等待时机
Then I'm gonna come back and kill Penguin
回来杀了企鹅
when the time is right.
听我说
Listen,
你知道我是为你好
you know I have your best interests at heart.
别回来了
Don't come back.
不  我会回来的
No. You will see me again.
在此期间  帮个忙
And in the meantime, do me a favor.
找到布奇
Find Butch.
如果他还活着  帮帮他
And if he's alive, help him.
我会的
I will.
再见了
See you soon.
保重
Be good.
当然
Always.
再见
Good night.
再见  警探
Night, Detective.
那大块头去找你了
That big guy visit you?
给你我捎去的包裹了
Give you the package I sent?
嗯  谢谢
Yeah. Thanks. That was, uh...
那么我们扯平了
Yo, this... so this means we're even?
我照你的意思供出了弗拉斯
I ratted out Flass like you wanted.
你不会再伤害我了吧
So now you back off, right?
我妻子不会有事了吧
Nothing more is gonna happen to my wife?
她安全了  我家人都安全了
She's safe? My family's safe?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't understand what you're talking about.
好吧  算了
Okay, okay, no worries.
听我说
Look,
就当我没问过
never mind I pressed.
我什么都不会跟人说
I won't say nothing to no one.
我会装作我们没说过这些话
I'll-I'll pretend this conversation never happened.
好吗  求你
Okay? Just...
别伤害我老婆孩子
keep my wife and kids out of it.
我求你
I'm-I'm begging you.
求你
Please.
求你了
Please! Please!
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com